<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Porfolio on Christopher Pintado</title>
    <link>https://cris-pintado.github.io/Porfolio1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in my Porfolio on Christopher Pintado</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cris-pintado.github.io/Porfolio1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analytical Review for Consolidating Habitat Mapping
            Within Europe: Insights from Portugal, Spain, and France</title>
      <link>https://cris-pintado.github.io/Porfolio1/post/project_1/</link>
      <pubDate> September 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cris-pintado.github.io/Porfolio1/post/project_1/</guid>
      <description>This paper addresses the challenges of standardizing habitat classification across three conterminous European countries by presenting a comparative analysis of habitat data for Portugal, Spain and
France with focus on the cross-border regions between these countries. This master's dissertation contributes to the InCASE project -In Situ
showcase Supporting Climate and Environmental Monitoring
in Europe- funded by the European Commission in support
to the European Environmental Agency (EEA) and the
Copernicus InSitu Component </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Approaches for Geometric Correction</title>
      <link>https://cris-pintado.github.io/Porfolio1/post/project_2/</link>
      <pubDate>January 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cris-pintado.github.io/Porfolio1/post/project_2/</guid>
      <description>GoExperimental outlook for geometric correction of various remote imaging sources utilizing manual and automatics approach. This project tries to convey the procedure of geometric corrections of satellite images that are not
            georeferenced directly, and are assigned arbitrary coordinate units of pixels, and converting them into a
            desired georeferenced coordinate system, using both manual and automatic models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiometric Image Correction</title>
      <link>https://cris-pintado.github.io/Porfolio1/post/project_3/</link>
      <pubDate> January 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cris-pintado.github.io/Porfolio1/post/project_3/</guid>
      <description>Having geometrically referenced images poses challenges, including atmospheric
  conditions, varied illumination due to solar position at acquisition time, and reliefinduced shadows. These factors deviate from the desired traits for remote sensing. This
  endeavor aims to outline the procedures involved in acquiring and radiometrically
  correcting satellite orthoimages, like Landsat-5 TM, utilizing both manual and automatic
  applications. The goal of radiometric correction is to transform digital sensor values into
  meaningful physical quantities, such as reflectance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Display of Fotointerpretation</title>
      <link>https://cris-pintado.github.io/Porfolio1/post/project_4/</link>
      <pubDate>February 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cris-pintado.github.io/Porfolio1/post/project_4/</guid>
      <description>Description: The photointerpretation of the FincaL.POL boundary involved analyzing surfaces, resolving ambiguities in vegetation and water features, and addressing technical issues to ensure accurate, validated results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering SQL: Building a Foundation Through Practice</title>
      <link>https://cris-pintado.github.io/Porfolio1/post/project_5/</link>
      <pubDate>March 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cris-pintado.github.io/Porfolio1/post/project_5/</guid>
      <description>Description: I’ve developed a solid foundation in SQL through hands-on practice, focusing on database design, query optimization, and data analysis with tools like MiraBosc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 6: Car Price Estimator</title>
      <link>https://cris-pintado.github.io/Porfolio1/post/project_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cris-pintado.github.io/Porfolio1/post/project_6/</guid>
      <description>Description:As an aspiring GIS professional, HTML development has become an essential tool in my skill set, enabling me to create structured, interactive, and visually engaging web pages. My focus lies in crafting clean and semantic HTML5 code that ensures both functionality and accessibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
